<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Elena Juarez Blog Thoughts</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Elena Juarez Blog Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gospel of Gaussian</title>
      <link>/post/the-gospel-of-gaussian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-gospel-of-gaussian/</guid>
      <description>As someone who has taken a number of college-level statistics classes (and quite enjoyed them), I took them as I was given, and I accepted the general principles as gospel. I have since found out, that how statistics, probability, and risk are taught, and what I believed to be “truth” and a surety, is actually just another hypothesis (ironic, right?). We are taught that nothing is 100%, but I never thought (or was taught) to question and be skeptical of how “modern-day” statistics and probability is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Depreciation for Dummies</title>
      <link>/post/depreciation-for-dummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/depreciation-for-dummies/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that the United States tax-code-makers are actually not the worst? Did you know that they aren’t trying to squeeze you out for everything you are worth? Did you know that they actually want you to build families, be independent, and get an advanced education? Honestly, I didn’t! But through a project that I am currently working on, I have come to find out that they have created and allowed innumerable ways for Americans to save money, and even incentivize certain things like getting married, having children, going to school, preparing for retirement, and starting a business?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Biggest Mistake a Consultant Makes (and how to avoid it)</title>
      <link>/post/the-biggest-mistake-a-consultant-makes-and-how-to-avoid-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-biggest-mistake-a-consultant-makes-and-how-to-avoid-it/</guid>
      <description>If you have ever been a consultant for a company or individual, one of the first things you do when getting started is meet with your contact about the project you have been newly assigned to. You may walk into this meeting with feelings of excitement or maybe even nervousness. If you are a good consultant, in that meeting you will be taking notes, asking questions, and regurgitating information back to assure that you are understanding things correctly and fully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>